# **Kyle Romero**

kgromero@gmail.com (281) 857-9006 https://kgromero.com

Hello! My name is Kyle Romero. I am a softw are development manager, with full-stack senior softw are development experience, living in Houston, Texas. I have a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering from Texas Tech University, and have worked in the IT field since 2007 in softw are engineering. Currently, I am a manager of operations technology, and previously was a team lead and senior developer at Worldwide Machinery, and a technical lead at HP I have extensive knowledge of all aspects of a successful software project, and have used many different technologies and methodologies over the years.

Linkedin kyleromero Github romero927

#### **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES	C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET, Typescript, ES5, ES2015
DATABASES	MSSQL
SCRIPTING	Bash, Pow ershell (Novice)
FRAMEWORKS	.NET 4.5, .NET 3.5, .NET 2.0, ASP.NET MVC WebAPI, Angular, React, React-Router, Redux, Redux-Thunk, Webpack, Babel, SuperAgent, SCSS, Bootstrap, JQuery
DEVELOPMENT TOOLS	GIT (Bitbucket, GitKraken / Bash), Azure DevOps, SVN (TortoiseSVN), Visual Studio 2015, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, TeamCity, JIRA, Trello, Azure DevOps, Windows 10/8.1/7, Linux (Ubuntu), MacOS Sierra, IIS, Node + NPM / YARN + Express + PM2, NGINX Reverse Proxy, Docker (Novice), Azure, Digital Ocean, LucidCharts
FORMER PROFICIENCIES	Java, C (Microcontroller), C++, Matlab, Verilog / VHDL, Perl

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### InfraSource, A Quanta Services Company

Operations Technology Manager Oct 2017 - Present

Construction and Professional Services (Natural Gas, Oil, and Electric Power Industry)

- Managing a team of internal and outsourced developers
- Manage DevOps, CICD, and PM processes using Azure DevOps
- Architect and explore new technology solutions
- Develop modern web application using Angular/React, HTML5, and CSS3; hosted on IIS
- Develop RESTful API using ASP.NET MVC WebAPI
- Server administration (Window's Servers)
- Azure Administration

## **Worldwide Machinery**

Team Lead / Senior Software Developer Apr 2016 - Oct 2017

Heavy Machinery Rental and Sales Company

- Manage project w orkflow using Agile Scrum methodology
- Manage junior developers' w orkloads
- Develop modern ASP.NET MVC WebAPI
- Develop modern Mobile-first Web Application using React, Redux, Typescript (ES6), Node.js + Express + NPM, Babel, Webpack, and SASS
- Maintain legacy ERP application using .NET Winforms (C#, MS SQL)
- Implement and Maintain Project and DevOps Processes using: JIRA, Bitbucket (GIT), TeamCity, Trello, Slack, Lucidcharts
- Proactively identify process improvements, as well as project opportunities
- Maintain / troubleshoot hardware infrastructure as needed (Windows / Ubuntu Servers)

# HP Inc.

Technical Lead (IT Developer / Engineer III) Dec 2014 - Feb 2016

Consumer IT Products

- Led development team w orking on enterprise level product quality / escalation management tool.
- Helped manage both onshore and offshore, full time and contingent developers.
- Helped to define and improve processes used on project, including development of a customized disciplined agile methodology and setting project timelines.
- Administered Team Foundation Server (source and requirements).
- Managed quality control and workloads for developers on project.
- Managed release process for tool.
- Worked with business to define requirements and develop architecture for project.
- Familiar with all aspects of project, from both technical and business standpoints.
- While w orking on .NET Applications, received exposure to Big Data technologies, such as Hadoop and HP Vertica, as well as Dashboarding Technologies, such as Qlikview and Tableau.
- During the year 2015, led team to successfully complete clone of our systems to be used on both sides of HP after the company split into two.

#### HP Inc.

Software Developer (IT Developer / Engineer II) Nov 2011 - Dec 2014

- Worked on ASP.NET Web applications incorporating a 3-Tier approach.
- Did w ork on all three tiers (MS SQL Database, VB.NET Middle tier object libraries, and ASP.NET + jQueryUl frontend).

- Project w as managed using Agile Scrum methodology (Received Certified Scrum Master certification 2012).
- Source control system w as Team Foundation Server.

## X-Fab Texas, Inc.

Software / Systems Engineer Dec 2009 - Nov 2011

Pure-play Semiconductor Foundry

- Development of ASP.NET/C# Web applications to serve as frontends for MSSQL databases.
- Developed .NET Web / Console / Winforms Applications.
- Involved in Database Design. Administered Windows and Linux servers.
- Designed Shell / Batch scripts. Developed C++ console applications.
- Deployed machine monitoring system. Developed Inventory tracking system.
- Deployed Documentation system to sites globally.

#### X-Fab Texas, Inc.

IT Intern May 2007 - Dec 2009

Internship between TTU EE Department and X-Fab, Texas

■ Developed various internal softw are projects, including statistical analysis programs, format conversion softw are, and .NET web applications.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Texas Tech University**

Aug 2005 - Dec 2009

Bachelor of Science - Computer Engineering GPA: 2.944

## **REFERENCES**

— Available Upon Request